<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advent Over the Wire 2021 on Joe Lothan</title><link>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/</link><description>Recent content in Advent Over the Wire 2021 on Joe Lothan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 10:37:09 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day 0 - Warmup</title><link>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/00-warmup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 15:51:25 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/00-warmup/</guid><description>Challenge Description Due to some Grinchey shenanigans, this year the OverTheWire Advent Bonanza CTF will run from Tuesday December 07 until Sunday December 19, however, as is tradition we have a cosy day0 warmup challenge from Retr0id to keep you busy:
Be sure to keep the flag for when the CTF begins, the flag format is AOTW{???}.
Overview We&amp;rsquo;re given a PNG, but after some investigation, we find it&amp;rsquo;s not just a PNG.</description></item><item><title>Day 9 - Santas Secrets</title><link>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/09-santas-secrets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 17:35:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/09-santas-secrets/</guid><description>Challenge Description Santa built a service to allow elves to encrypt secret data without having access to the keys.
(Download Files)
Overview We&amp;rsquo;re given a python webserver with an encrypted flag and the key that was used to encrypt it, but we can only read the encrypted flag and use the key to encrypt data, not read the key itself. Using a bug in python data encoding, we can overwrite successive bytes of the key, use it to encrypt known data, and brute force the entire key, using it to decrypt the flag.</description></item><item><title>Day 7 - Jigsaw</title><link>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/07-jigsaw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 11:14:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/07-jigsaw/</guid><description>Challenge Description Santa has hidden a secret message on the backside of a jigsaw puzzle that he completed. Sadly, one of his elves dropped the completed puzzle, shuffling all the pieces. Can you verify that it is indeed impossible for the Grinch to recover this message?
Downloaded File
Overview We are given a bunch of PNGs with jigsaw pieces on them, looking at their metadata we can order them and extract a secret message</description></item><item><title>Day 12 - Christmas Truce</title><link>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/12-christmas-true/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 10:37:09 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://joe.lothan.net/ctfs/2021-advent-otw/12-christmas-true/</guid><description>Challenge Description Santa and Grinch forces have declared a fragily truce. It is your job to keep the truce going by keeping Christmas cheer high. Read more on how to do this by following the provided link. (that link)
Overview For this challenge, you had to make pancakes and soup, donate to a charity, and/or wear christmas clothes to get a flag. No, really.
Hardest flag to find? A good looking christmas sweater.</description></item></channel></rss>